

# Raban Ohlhoff

**Master Architect** 

#### **PROFILE**

Address Tempelhof,

Berlin - 12101

Germany

Website

Email Address ohlhoff.architecture@gmail.com

Date Of Birth

Researchgate

Raban\_Ohlhoff

**Twitter** 

@Raban\_Ohlhoff

**LinkedIn**Raban Ohlhoff

**Github** Raban\_Ohlhoff

#### **ACHIEVEMENT**

Bachelor Diplome
Université libre de Bruxelles

July 2020

ECTS Grade: A with Distinction

Exposition / Presentation

Faculté d'architecture ULB

June 2020

**ArchiExpo** 

**Project Exposition** 

Faculté d'architecture ULB

May 2019

## **LANGUAGES**

**German** Native Tongue French Very Fluent

**English**Very Fluent

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Office Suite

**ArchiCAD** 

AutoCAD

SketchUp

Blender

Sverchok

**QCAD** 

**FreeCAD** 

**Python** 

Inkscape

GIMP

#### **OBJECTIVE**

During my architecture studies I was able to gain a lot of passionate experience and knowledge, but now that it is coming to an end, I am looking forward to opportunities to get to know the reality of architectural work and to use my acquired skills in a beneficial way. My studies consisted largely of creative group work, through which I discovered my passion for coordination, communication, and collaboration.

What appeals to me about architecture is creativity and organized design. My interests are increasingly moving towards parametric design and machine learning aided conceptual design.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

## FabLab, Brussels, BEL

Student

(January 2020 - June 2020)

- Worked as a team member of a multidisciplinary workshop.
- Learned to work with 3d printers, lasercut and cnc milling machines.
- Extended my knowledge of various open-source software through several training courses.
- Developed independent multi-phase working and communication skills.
   Key Achievement: Designed and materialized new prototypes of an automatic shading system.

#### Les Fumades, Carcassonne, FR

Intern, Construction supervisor

(April 2017 - June 2017)

- Worked as planner and woodworker in a carpentry.
- Learned the complete process from the living tree to the finished wooden cabin.
- Experienced the physical and mental work of timber construction.
   Key Achievement: Designed and built an elevated wooden cottage.

## Foyer de Vie, Ruzière, FR

Intern, Educator

(March 2016 - September 2016)

- Worked passionately with people with mental and physical disabilities
- Gardening and organizational work done as a team.
- Learned to work with different people and how to coordinate small groups.

# **EDUCATION**

Université libre de Bruxelles, Bruxelles, BEL

Master Architecture

(September 2020 - Present)

Université libre de Bruxelles, Bruxelles, BEL

Bachelor Architecture

(September 2017 - September 2020)

ECTS grade : A

Beethoven-Gymnasium, Berlin, DE

(July 2009 - July 2015) 2.1 German GPA

**Abitur** General

2.1 definant of A

## SKILLS

Creative Expertise

Drawing Advanced

Advanced

Advance

Organization

Computer-aided Design
Intermediate

Advanced

**Problem Solving** 

Coordination Intermediate

Advanced

## **PROJECTS**

# Responsive Facades

https://sinasta.github.io/responsive\_facade.html

Project realized within the digital fabrication studio. By means of an experimental and analytical approach, the functionality of automated facade systems is evaluated, followed by a simulation of the energy balance and light irradiation.

## Centrale Weerkplaatsen renovation [Concept]

 $https://sinasta.github.io/cohabitat\_renovation.html\\$ 

Renovation project as part of my architecture studies. The focus of this work is on a non-invasive renovation to transform a classical apartment block into a cohabitation and by that, to enable a community life.

# REFERENCES

Philippe Meyer Founder of Cabanes des Fumades cabanesdesfumades@orange.fr **David Erkan**Founder of LAD
David.Erkan@ulb.be

Albert Werckmann Founder of Foyer de Vie secretariat@ruziere.fr